# **AUSTIN POOR**

@ austinpoor@gmail.com

**(**203) 558-4619

Queens, NY

in linkedin.com/in/austinpoor

github.com/a-poor

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Scientist**

#### **Metis Data Science Bootcamp**

m Jan 2020 - March 2020

New York, NY

Highly selective, accredited 12-week immersive data science bootcamp focused on Python, statistical modeling, machine learning, visualization, and communication of results. See projects below.

#### Assistant to the Executive Creative Director **CHRIX**

M Oct 2014 - Aug 2017

New York, NY

Responsible for managing Executive Creative Director's priorities, schedule, and following employee task progress. On behalf of the ECD, coordinated with producers and technical staff on client project delivery assignments and issue resolution. Further, served as fill-in technical resource on multiple projects. Worked with clients such as Nike, Cinnamon Toast Crunch, Verizon FiOS, and Subway.

## **PROJECTS**

## Save the Dinosaurs: Creating a Bot to Play the Chrome Dino Game

Using deep reinforcement learning to train an agent to play the Chrome "No-Internet" Dinosaur game.

- Used Selenium to control Chrome and test the bots' performance
- Created multiple "heuristic" bots to play based on hard-coded rules
- Used grid-search to optimize the heuristic bot's strategy
- Created a Deep Q-Learning bot using Tensorflow
- Got high score: 17,959 (about 5x the avg human high score)

Here's a link to the repo: github.com/a-poor/chrome-dino-solver

#### AustinRecommendsMovies.com

Built a Fask web app to recommend movies to users using collaborative filtering and content-based filtering.

- Merged three large datasets (movie plot summaries, user reviews, movie metadata)
- · Stored data using PostgreSQL and GCP
- Used NMF to create topic vectors based on film summaries
- · Calculate user-user and film-film similarity using SQL
- Collaborative filtering: Recommend movies liked by similar users
- Content-based filtering: Recommend movies by plot-vector similarity
- User stats: Used Bokeh to plot user-rating distributions

Here's a link to the repo: github.com/a-poor/movie-recs

#### Spotify Skip Prediction

Analyzed Spotify data on user listening sessions to predict the likelihood of a user skipping a song.

- Stored the large dataset in PostgreSQL on AWS
- · Used feature engineering to account for sequential data
- Performed classification with multiple model types
- LightGBM Classifier got a final accuracy of 0.73

Read more about it here: https://towardsdatascience.com/predicting-spotify-track-skips-49cf4a48b2a5 And here's a link to the repo: github.com/a-poor/spotify-skip-prediction

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BA** - Computer Science

#### Sarah Lawrence College

M Sept 2017 - Dec 2019

Pronxville, NY

Studied computer science with a focus on data science. Each course involved a semester-long, in-depth project related to the course. Select courses:

- Bio-Inspired Artificial Intelligence Select project topics:
- Databases

Computer Organization.

- Flask App for College Student Course Sign-Up
- Predicting the Political Leaning of News Articles with Deep Learning
- · Used data science tools to investigated litigation practices in NYC housing court focusing on improper service of process

#### **University of Connecticut**

M Sept 2012 - June 2014

Storrs, CT

#### Took courses towards a BA in Communications

## **SUMMARY**

I combine 3 years of business executive support in a fast-paced digital animation firm, including influential coordination and management in highly collaborative team environments, with recent data science technical skills and hands-on experience. My data science skills include data extraction and preparation, data queries and analysis, and audienceappropriate data visualization, utilizing my years of commercial design experience. I am looking for a position to prove the value of my technical, critical thinking, communication, and team coordination skills and experience.

### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

- Python
- SQL

Matplotlib

Seaborn

 Plotly D3.js

Flask

XGBoost

LightGBM

- JavaScript
- Bash

#### Tools/Packages

- Pandas
- Numpy/SciPy
- Sci-kit Learn
- NLTK
- SpaCy Tensorflow
- PvTorch
- BeautifulSoup
- Selenium
- PySpark
- Dask Tableau
- - Docker

## **Databases**

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Heroku

## **Cloud Providers**

- AWS
- GCP

## Other

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator